Ms. Suenaga!
老師！
Hold on, I'm coming!
等我，我現在就來！
Are you okay?
妳還好嗎？
Let's rest there.
去那邊休息吧
It's your fault!
都是你害的！
It's all your fault.
全部都是你害的
If I never met you,
如果我沒有遇見你
I'd still be working at the school.
我還會留在學校
I could've stayed a teacher.
我還能繼續當老師
But I don't know anymore,
我已經不知道該怎麼辦了
what kind of excuse I can give,
我到底該找什麼藉口
what I can blame it on.
該怪罪於什麼原因？
I love you.
我喜歡黑岩
As it is now, nobody will understand.
現在這樣沒有人會理解我們
You'd just get blamed for everything,
大家只會怪老師妳
I don't want you to shoulder it all.
我不想讓妳背負一切
Thank you.
謝謝你
I hoped to find you here!
你們果然在這裡！
I'm so glad you're alive!
太好了，你們還活著！
I promise to protect you from now on.
我會守護妳的
Do you know what kind of commotion you're causing?
妳知道現在引起多大的風波嗎？
This could be a crime!
這可是犯罪啊！
Thank you for letting me stay.
謝謝你的照顧
Yup.
好
That's it?
就這樣？
This is bee's wax.
這個叫蜂蠟
It comes from a beehive.
是用蜂巢做成的
We use it like this to mend cracks.
我們像這樣用它修復裂痕
I probably
我也許
kept sending those letters to your mother
是想藉著一直寄信給愛子
to try to mend the cracks
試著彌補
I made years ago in our relationship.
過去我造成的裂痕
But unlike wood,
但是跟木頭不一樣
the cracks in people
人與人之間的裂痕
can't be mended so easily.
很難修復
But
但是
you still have time.
你還來得及
Thanks.
謝謝你
I'll come back here to see you again.
我會再來這裡的，來見爸爸你
Mr. Shimazaki.
島崎先生
Here, take this.
來，給妳
Thank you.
謝謝
Thank you so much for all your help.
那個，承蒙您的諸多照顧了
It's nothing.
不客氣
Please…
拜託…
Please look after
請幫我
Akira for me.
照顧阿晶
Ms. Suenaga.
老師
I got a text from Akira!
我收到阿晶的訊息了！
What?
什麼？
Hold on.
等等
SORRY FOR WORRYING YOU. I'M COMING HOME TODAY.
（抱歉讓妳擔心了，今天就回家）
Finally.
終於
I guess he's done running away from home.
我猜他不再離家出走了
Thank goodness.
謝天謝地
He's going to come back with her, isn't he?
他會跟那個女的一起回來吧？
JOFFE WILL COME PICK YOU UP.
（喬飛會去接你）
Will you call me this time?
這次妳會打給我嗎？
I want to see you again.
我還想再跟妳見面
We have to talk to your mother.
我們必須跟你母親好好談談
And I'll also decide on my career path.
我也會決定志願
I'll work to gain her acceptance
我會努力讓她接受我們
and then
然後
think about our future.
也會考慮我們的未來
Thank you.
謝謝你
Sorry to have worried you.
抱歉讓你擔心了
Mom?
媽媽？
What are you doing, Hijiri!
妳在做什麼，聖！
-What are you doing? -Don't blame her.
-妳到底在做什麼？ -不是她的錯
-Akira. -I can explain.
-阿晶 -我可以解釋的
Just come with me!
好了，跟我來！
Ms. Suenaga!
老師！
So he called you first,
所以是他先打電話給妳
and you went after him because you were worried he was acting strange.
妳去找他是因為擔心他不太對勁
Yes.
對
Then--
然後…
The ferry just happened to get cancelled and you couldn't get home.
因為船班不巧停駛才回不來
Kuroiwa stayed at his father's place.
黑岩同學住在他父親家裡
Yes.
是
You were only worried about him as his teacher, right?
妳只是作為老師才擔心他，對吧？
-Yes, at first-- -Oh, good.
-最初確實是… -哦，太好了
I almost had a heart attack.
差點嚇死我了
I assumed you two did something stupid.
我還以為你們兩個已經做了蠢事
Kuroiwa's mother was so worried.
黑岩同學的母親也非常擔心
I'm here to talk about your daughter.
我想跟您談談您女兒的事
My son isn't coming home.
我兒子沒有回家
After searching everywhere,
到處找過之後
we found out he's with Ms. Suenaga.
終於得知他跟末永老師在一起
Please, would you get in touch with her?
請問您現在能聯絡她嗎？
But I couldn't get through to your phone.
可是妳的手機都打不通
It got wet in the rain and broke.
手機被雨淋濕，壞掉了
Well, we got even more worried.
害我們更加擔心
That's why…
所以才…
I'm sorry for hitting you.
對不起，打了妳一巴掌
But Mom, I…
但是媽媽，我…
It's okay.
沒關係
We'll go see Ms. Kuroiwa tomorrow and tell her what you just told me.
我們明天就去見黑岩小姐 把剛才的話告訴她
Once you explain,
只要妳解釋清楚
she's sure to understand.
她一定會諒解的
It'll be okay.
沒事的
Now.
好了
My tie!
我的領帶！
You can stay home from school today.
你今天可以待在家不用去上學
My phone!
我的手機！
Um…
那個…
You can go back tomorrow.
我是希望你明天再去啦
What happened?
到底發生了什麼事？
What about your Dad?
你也還沒告訴我們你父親的事
How about the two of us go to a public bath and have a nice talk?
要不然今天 我們就一起去公共澡堂談談吧？
I promise we'll talk when I get home.
回來再慢慢說
Yeah?
是嗎？
And have you thought about what you did? Feeling remorseful?
你有在反省自己犯下的錯嗎？ 有感到後悔嗎？
Yeah.
有
So I'm going to school.
所以我現在要去學校
Bye.
再見
I'm so sorry about this.
真的很抱歉
Come in.
請進
As I understand, my son first called you
所以據我理解，是我兒子先打給老師
and dragged you into this.
才把老師捲進來
Is that correct?
妳是這個意思吧？
No, that's not what we're trying to say.
不，我們並不是那個意思
It all started three years ago.
全部都是起因於三年前
You are understandably worried.
您會擔心也是當然的事
Please accept my apology.
實在非常抱歉
Hijiri just went to chaperon.
聖只是陪著他
She was concerned as his former teacher.
因為曾擔任班導，無法坐視不管
She simply ensured he made it safely to his father, nothing more.
她只是確保他 安全地找到他的父親，僅此而已
Right, Hijiri?
對吧，聖？
I'm sorry, Mom.
對不起，媽媽
Hijiri.
聖
I'm very sorry.
非常對不起
I love your son.
我喜歡黑岩
Not as a teacher.
並非以老師的身分
I'm in love with him.
我喜歡他
What are you saying?
妳在胡說什麼？
What's gotten into you?
妳怎麼了？
Hijiri?
聖？
Do you know what you're saying?
妳知道自己在說什麼嗎？
I do.
我知道
I understand your judgment.
我明白妳的決定
-But-- -Then!
-但是… -既然如此！
Stop this!
就別再這樣做了！
How many times are you going to repeat the same mistake?
妳到底要重蹈覆轍幾次？
Apologize to Ms. Kuroiwa, and swear you'll never see her son again!
現在就向黑岩小姐道歉 並答應她不會再跟她兒子見面
Hijiri!
聖！
I can't do that.
我辦不到
I can't…
我無法…
I can't keep lying.
我無法再繼續說謊了
I promise you,
我答應妳
I won't do anything to hinder your son's life.
我不會妨礙黑岩同學的生活
Not until
直到
I get your blessing.
妳願意接受我為止
If only I could tell you
阿晶就拜託妳了
that you have my blessing.
如果我能這樣說就好了
But
但是
I can't do that.
我實在說不出口
For Akira right now,
阿晶現在
being around you makes him unstable.
只要跟老師妳在一起，就會很不穩定
Just like three years ago.
三年前也是如此
The two of you
你們兩人
were so desperate to explore your feelings,
一心只顧著確認彼此的心意
you became blind,
就會變得盲目
and lost so much.
失去了很多東西
Both of your lives will be ruined at this rate.
這樣下去，你們都會完蛋
For right now,
現在
if we work hard to do what we can,
我們會各自努力做好能做的事
waiting for the right time--
等到時機成熟…
You say you will wait,
妳說妳會等
but how can you have so much faith?
可是妳怎能深信不疑呢？
Akira is still just 18.
阿晶才十八歲喔
What if Akira has a change of heart, and falls for someone else.
如果他中途變心喜歡上別人
If that were to happen, the one who would lose everything
如果那樣的話，到時會失去一切的人
is you.
可是老師妳喔
I believe in Kuroiwa.
我相信黑岩同學
Besides,
而且
even if that happens,
即便走到那一步
I wouldn't regret it.
我也不後悔
When I heard you two were on the island,
當我聽到你們一起在島上時
I thought it was some kind of kidnapping or something.
我認為這應該算是某種程度的誘拐
Akira's still in high school.
阿晶還只是高中生
A minor.
是未成年
You are also a teacher.
更別提妳是老師
It is only natural for you
妳自然
to take responsibility.
會需要負起責任吧
Hijiri!
聖！
I also, haven't said everything I've wanted to.
我也是不會再多說什麼了
If this continues,
如果妳繼續下去
I will have to take legal action.
我將採取法律行動
Please, anything but that!
請您別這麼做！
She…
她…
She doesn't understand
她不明白
what she's doing is a crime
自己做的事可能是一種犯罪
that can be punished.
會遭受懲罰
She's just getting swept up by emotion.
現在只是一時沖昏了頭
I promise to make her listen.
我會好好勸她
She's actually such a good person.
她其實是個好孩子
Whenever I catch a cold,
我感冒的時候
she comes to help around the house immediately
她總是會馬上回來幫我做家事
like a good daughter.
是個懂事的女兒
But now,
但她現在
it's like the floodgates have been opened.
只是一時失控
She'll come to her senses soon.
她很快就會恢復理智的
I promise to make her listen.
我會好好勸她
So please…
所以求求妳…
Please!
拜託妳！
Please
拜託妳
don't press charges!
請您高抬貴手！
Ms. Suenaga.
老師
Please
拜託妳
understand our feelings.
體諒我們的心情吧
Please don't
請別再
break your parents' hearts any further.
讓妳父母更傷心了
Please don't make them
請不要讓他們
go through this.
經歷這一切
I'm really sorry for all of that.
真的很對不起
But I want you to understand how I feel some day.
但我想讓妳明白我的感受
Are you really prepared for it?
妳真的有相應的覺悟嗎？
Being with him
和他在一起
means you can't teach anymore.
就代表不能繼續當老師
You'll lose everything you've worked for.
過去所有的努力都會付諸流水
Is that what you want?
妳真的要這樣做嗎？
If you see him again, she will sue you.
如果妳再跟他見面，她一定會提告
What will you do then?
變成那樣的話，妳該怎麼辦？
This love can never happen.
這段戀情不可能會有結果
Just give it up.
快放棄吧
I met Dad.
我見到爸爸了
I know, he just called me.
我知道，剛才他打給我了
What?
什麼？
I'm sorry
對不起
that I had trouble talking to you
我都沒好好跟你說
about your Dad.
你父親的事
I'm sorry too
我才是
for taking off.
就這樣走了
But Ms. Suenaga was with me, helping me talk to him, so I--
不過，因為有老師陪著我 幫我跟他說了很多話，所以我…
She came here with her mother today.
她今天跟她的母親來過了
She told me everything, including your feelings.
她把所有都告訴我了 還有你們的想法
But I told her that I can't allow
可是我告訴她，我終究無法同意
your relationship.
你們的關係
I'm about to decide my career
之後我會決定志願
and think about my future.
好好考慮未來的事
She's the one
我會這樣想
who got me to.
全都歸功於老師
So even if it's not now,
因此即便不是現在也沒關係
I want you to accept her some day.
希望妳有一天能接受她
Come back home.
那就回家吧
That will be a start.
回家我們再來談
Okay.
我知道了
SHOTARO KAWAI
（川合勝太郎）
Have a good day.
我先告辭了
Good work.
辛苦了
Could we go somewhere and talk?
那個，我們能找個地方談談嗎？
I guess not, since we're not together anymore.
果然不行啊，畢竟我們都分手了
I'm willing to listen. Is this about Hijiri?
我可以陪你聊聊，是小聖的事嗎？
She came back.
她好像回來了
With the boy?
跟那男孩一起嗎？
She went to his mother and told her she loves him.
回來之後，向他母親說自己喜歡他了
She said she was going to wait until she received her blessing.
還說未來會一直等到她同意
I see.
是嗎
She finally--
她終於…
She finally went crazy. She's like a different person.
終於整個人瘋了 小聖根本變了一個人
She finally admitted it.
她終於說出口了
What?
什麼？
It took her a while to be able to say she loved him.
她真是花了很長的時間 才終於承認自己的心意
I hope she can be happy.
希望她能得到幸福
Of course she can't!
她怎麼可能幸福！
I knew you two wouldn't last.
我就知道你們不會順利
Let's go, we'll be late.
走吧，我們要遲到了
Seriously?
搞什麼？
I'll be going home tonight, okay?
今天我就先回去了，好嗎？
What?
回去？
Why?
為什麼？
I need to go to school tomorrow and tell them everything.
明天還要去學校跟大家解釋
Tell them what?
解釋什麼？
About the incident three years ago.
三年前跟黑岩同學的事情
I'll be explaining it to the parents.
我得跟家長們說清楚
But with what just happened,
不過因為這次的事
I don't think I can stay.
我應該是待不下去了
Then…
那麼…
you won't teach again?
妳不會再當教師了？
Thanks for dinner.
我吃飽了
You should try to break your lease
妳趕快退掉現在的住處
and move back here.
搬回家裡來吧
Okay.
是
MS. HIJIRI / OTOHA
（聖老師，乙葉）
Hijiri!
聖！
I was worried when you were gone for two days!
兩天都找不到人，讓我擔心死了
Felt under the weather?
身體不舒服嗎？
So with that former student?
所以妳是跟之前那個學生？
I'm sorry.
對不起
I wanted to talk to you
我想早點
about this sooner if I could.
和妳說這件事
I'm thinking
我也打算…
I should quit as well.
從這所學校辭職
Okay.
我知道了
Then never think of becoming a teacher again.
那妳別再想當老師了
I trusted the incident three years ago
我原本相信三年前的那件事
wouldn't be repeated.
以後不會再發生的
You've really disappointed me.
妳讓我太失望了
You're not qualified to be a teacher anymore.
妳沒資格再當老師
I'm sorry.
對不起
Look what you threw away.
看吧，妳捨棄的東西
You were supposed to retake your certification, right?
妳本來要重新接受面試吧？
Becoming a class room teacher was your goal.
再次擔任班導是妳的目標吧
But in the end, this possibly fleeting relationship
但結果，與一個小妳十歲的男孩
with a boy ten years your junior was more important to you.
談場曇花一現的戀愛 對妳來說更重要
You're a teacher who messed with a minor.
妳是對未成年出手的女老師
That truth won't go away.
妳無法抹滅這個事實
Even if you worked 100 times harder than anyone,
未來就算妳比別人努力百倍
you can't even be on the starting line.
都無法再站上起跑線
But you're fine with that because you love him, right?
不過妳喜歡他，所以都無所謂吧？
You love him.
妳喜歡他
That gets to be your convenient excuse.
妳可以把這當成是任何事的藉口
Congratulations.
恭喜妳
I wish you the best.
祝妳幸福
Good morning!
早安！
GREET WITH A CHEERFUL SMILE
（面帶笑容打招呼）
Hey, Joffe.
嘿，喬飛
Yeah?
是
Where's Akira?
阿晶呢？
He's back home, right?
他回來了吧？
He wasn't upstairs.
他不在樓上
He stepped out to go to the convenience store.
他剛才出門說要去超商
I see.
是嗎？
Hello? Kuroiwa?
喂？是黑岩同學嗎？
Ms. Suenaga?
老師？
Is it really you?
真的是老師嗎？
I haven't bought a new phone yet.
我還沒買手機
Mom said you came to see her.
我聽我媽說妳來過家裡了
I'm sorry I wasn't there.
對不起，沒有陪在妳身邊
It's okay.
沒關係
Anyway, are you going to school?
別說這個了，你有去上學嗎？
Yeah, from home.
有啊，從家裡通學
Huh?
嗯？
I moved back home.
我回到家裡住了
Mom told me to.
照我媽說的
I see.
是嗎？
I'm sure she's relieved.
她一定放心多了
What about you?
老師呢？
Your school?
有去學校嗎？
Don't worry, I got that handled.
你不用擔心，我這邊很順利
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
It's the same as that day.
跟那天一樣
I wish I could go back and tell myself…
好想回到那時，告訴當時的我…
Tell yourself what?
說什麼？
Just how amazing
墜入愛河是
falling in love is.
多麼美妙的一件事
Akira!
阿晶！
Sorry, I have to go.
抱歉，我得掛了
Okay, later.
好吧，之後再聊
What's wrong?
妳怎麼了？
I forgot to buy something
我忘記在超商
from the convenience store.
買些東西
Bread for tomorrow!
明天的麵包！
Shotaro!
勝太郎！
Why are you here?
你怎麼來了？
I can't believe my mom asked you for advice.
沒想到我媽居然會找你商量
She asked me to come talk to you.
她問我能不能跟妳聊聊
I heard.
我聽說了
You're quitting teaching?
妳不當老師了嗎？
I'm planning on finding different work.
我打算去找別的工作
It's my own decision.
這是我自己的決定
It's all his fault.
都是那傢伙害的
I should have
更早之前
given up on teaching way before.
我就該放棄老師的工作了
I was being stubborn.
我太執著了
But now I'll just cause problems.
但現在這樣，只會給大家添麻煩
Then come with me.
那妳跟我走吧
-Let go. -I'm going to be assigned to Singapore.
-放開我 -我會被派駐去新加坡
Come with me, Hijiri.
聖，跟我走吧
I'm single again.
我跟原口小姐分手了
Hey.
等等
She said
她說
that I haven't moved on from you.
我現在還喜歡著妳
-No way. -I told myself no way.
-那不可能 -我原本也以為不可能
But I can't ignore you.
但我就是無法丟下妳不管
Back then,
我那個時候
I pushed you away, didn't even try to go after you.
我丟下了妳，完全沒去追妳
Whose fault is it that we're in this stupid, shameful situation…
是誰造成這麼愚蠢難堪的處境…
I'm sorry.
對不起
I should've fought to stay by your side.
我當時應該更努力陪在妳身邊
If you come with me, you can put this all behind you.
如果妳跟我走，就能忘掉這一切
-If you distance-- -Shotaro.
-只要跟他分開… -勝太郎
I'm sorry.
對不起
I can't go with you.
我不能跟你走
-Don't. -I already decided.
-別這樣 -我下定決心了
They'll shun you.
大家會覺得妳瘋了
I know you're serious about this.
我知道妳很認真
But
但是
the more serious you are, the crazier they'll think you are.
妳越是認真，大家只會更覺得妳瘋了
Being in love should be celebrated, but instead they'll think
喜歡一個人本應是受到祝福的 可是他們會覺得
you're stupid and crazy.
妳很笨而且瘋了
Are you okay with that?
妳這樣也無所謂嗎？
That's
這樣子
so painful.
未免太痛苦了
I don't expect people to understand.
我本就不奢求大家會明白
I'm going home.
我回去了
You quit your school rather quickly.
妳蠻快辭掉學校的工作呢
Twice at that.
還是兩次
I would take any job that doesn't ask for experience.
做什麼工作都沒關係 只要能接受新手
I'm willing to learn.
我願意從頭開始學習
Kuroiwa, I bought a cell phone.
黑岩，我買了手機
Contact me if you need me.
有什麼需要跟我聯絡
I'm home.
我回來了
This property?
這間房子嗎？
Yes.
是的
It's quite affordable, but you need a guarantor.
房租確實很便宜 可是還是需要保證人
Of course.
我想也是
It can be a relative or friend.
家人或朋友都可以
Just get them to sign here.
讓他們在這邊簽名
Okay, thank you. I'll be in touch.
好的，我會再聯繫
Hijiri.
小聖
Long time, how've you been?
好久不見，過得好嗎？
Guarantor?
保證人？
I don't want to burden my parents any more than I have.
我不想再給父母添麻煩了
Is there anything you could do?
我能不能拜託妳？
I need to quickly find work and a new place so I can move out.
我想快點找到工作跟新住處 然後搬出去
You've changed.
妳變了，小聖
You're stronger.
變堅強了
It's the opposite.
恰恰相反
I'm a mess.
我現在一團糟
But you have courage.
但妳有勇氣
A coward who lives righteously out of fear of judgment
因害怕別人眼光而合乎道德的懦夫
compared to a fighting hero who endures constant ridicule.
跟飽受各種惡言惡語 卻努力戰鬥去爭取的勇者
I will always support the heroes.
我永遠支持勇者
You're fighting.
小聖，妳在努力戰鬥
Thank you very much.
謝謝妳
Okay, I can be your guarantor.
好，我來當妳的保證人吧
Really?
真的嗎？
Sorry to put you on the spot.
很抱歉讓妳為難了
I promise not to bring you any trouble.
我保證絕對不會給妳添麻煩
-Thank you-- -Sorry, one sec.
-謝謝… -對不起，失陪一下
GUARANTOR: RITSU HARAGUCHI
（保證人，原口律）
KUROIWA
（黑岩）
Hello?
喂？
Ms. Suenaga?
老師？
What is it?
什麼事？
I won't be long.
我馬上就會掛斷
I went back to school,
最近我回去上課
so I've been thinking about my future.
想了很多關於未來的事
About you too.
還有老師的事
I was happy at first,
最初我確實很高興
but then I was over it.
但後來覺得膩了
I'm over you.
我膩了
So I wanted to tell you before we do anything
所以在我們做出 什麼無法挽回的事之前
we can't take back.
我想跟妳說清楚
Right now,
現在
I can't think about you.
我不能再想妳了
Why?
為什麼？
Let's
我們
not do this.
別再繼續下去了
Bye.
再見
An open campus?
校園參觀？
-This place seemed nice. -Let me see.
-我覺得這裡不錯 -讓我看看
I'm going to go check it out.
我要去看看
This place is like super famous.
這是超有名的名校吧？
They just had a teacher win a Nobel prize.
之前還有老師獲得諾貝爾獎
I can't believe you're thinking about going somewhere so challenging.
沒想到你會想去這麼難考的學校
I'm not sold yet.
我還沒決定
I want to check it out first.
先看過之後再說
For real?
真的嗎？
I feel happy.
我感覺好欣慰
Joffe is so happy.
喬飛好高興喔
Huh?
嗯？
-Look! -Hey! Oh, sorry.
-你看！ -喂！哦，對不起
Wow.
哇，好厲害
Let me know when you're finished.
看完之後請跟我說一聲
Direction, good.
方位，吉
No issue with the flow.
流通沒有問題
I don't sense negative energy.
也沒有感覺到什麼邪氣
This place seems good.
這裡應該很不錯
Hijiri?
小聖？
I'm sorry for making you come with me on a day off.
對不起，讓妳在休假陪我看房
I should be able to move here thanks to you.
多虧了妳，我應該可以搬來這裡
Although I have nothing.
雖然我一無所有
You do. You have him.
有啊，妳還有他
Last night,
昨晚
Kuroiwa told me
黑岩對我說
he's over me.
他膩了
That we should stop.
我們別再繼續下去了
What?
什麼？
Youth these days.
現在的年輕人
They change their minds so easily.
想法那麼容易變來變去
But I mean,
不過也是
I can't blame him.
我不能怪他
I'm way too old for him.
對他來說，我太老了
How could I be so dumb?
我怎麼會這麼笨呢？
It's okay, you can cry.
妳可以哭出來
You're free to smile, you're free to cry.
無論要笑要哭，都是妳的自由
Not having anything means you're free of attachments.
什麼都沒有 也代表妳不受任何東西束縛
Good morning.
早安
-I held Hijiri in my arms yesterday. -What?
-昨天我擁抱了小聖 -什麼？
-I became her guarantor for a new lease.
-我當了她新房子的保證人
The poor thing has nobody else she can turn to.
可憐的孩子，竟然沒有其他人能依靠
She cried in my arms.
她在我懷裡哭了
It means that's all it was.
終究是這種程度而已
I saw this coming a mile away.
早就預料到結果了
Totally expected.
預料之中
Hold up.
等等
What'd you say?
你剛才說了什麼？
Hijiri.
聖
A job agent is here for you.
哈囉工作人力仲介的人來了
-What? -They found work that might suit you.
-什麼？ -他們找到適合妳的工作了
They came here?
他們來這了？
-Ms. Haraguchi! -Hello.
-原口小姐！ -妳好
I'm here from Hello Work.
我是哈囉工作派來的
I have an interesting opportunity.
有一個工作想介紹給妳
-Where are we? Wait… -Hold on.
-我們在哪裡？等… -等一下
I'm supposed to meet the boy here.
來這裡應該能見到那個男孩
What?
什麼？
Department of science and engineering.
理工學系
Why don't you go talk to him.
妳就去跟他談談吧
There's nothing to say at this point.
現在沒什麼好說的
Why? You're not going to ask him?
為什麼？妳不問清楚嗎？
How do you not have questions?
妳怎麼會沒有疑惑？
Why the sudden change? Doesn't it seem weird?
為什麼突然變了？這不奇怪嗎？
If you have questions, you have to pursue them.
只要有疑惑就要查清楚
That's how we discovered the black hole, neutrinos, and cloning.
所以人才會發現黑洞 微中子跟克隆技術
Excuse me?
什麼？
Damn it!
該死！
You threw everything away and chose him, didn't you?
妳不是決定要捨棄一切選擇他嗎？
You're okay for it to end?
那妳甘願就這樣結束嗎？
Shouldn't you at least talk face to face
至少最後要面對面
one last time?
好好談一談吧？
If you miss this chance, you'll never see him again.
如果錯過這次機會 就不會再見到他了
Fight, Hijiri!
戰鬥吧，小聖
To be young.
青春啊
SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING
（理工學系）
Is this science and engineering?
請問理工學系是這邊嗎？
-Yes, right that way. -Okay.
-是，請往那邊走 -好
I'm sorry for just showing up. Wait!
對不起突然出現，等一下
Kuroiwa, just tell me why.
黑岩同學，請告訴我
Why did you decide
為什麼決定
on science and engineering?
理工學系？
What future did you see?
你看到什麼未來目標？
That's all.
這樣就好
Please tell me.
最後請告訴我這個
What about you?
老師妳呢？
What?
什麼？
You're giving up teaching?
妳不繼續教書了嗎？
You quit again
又因為我
because of me.
而辭職
Are you planning to never teach again?
以後再也不打算當老師了嗎？
How did you…?
你怎麼會知道…
I was told to really think about it.
那個人叫我仔細想清楚
Did you know Hijiri resigned?
你知道聖辭職了嗎？
Because of you.
都是因為你
That might be fine for you, you have a future.
你也許無所謂，你還有未來
You have dreams and goals.
還有夢想和目標
The world's your oyster.
要什麼有什麼
But Hijiri?
但聖呢？
What does she have?
她剩下什麼？
That's why all of a sudden…
所以你才突然…
Why didn't you tell me you quit?
為什麼不告訴我妳辭職了？
I didn't want to worry you right now.
現在不想讓你擔心
I think the way you do that is stupid.
我覺得妳這樣做很蠢
He was right.
那個人說的沒錯
I can't do anything.
我什麼忙都幫不上
Except distance myself.
除了離開妳之外
I don't want you to quit teaching.
我不想看妳辭職
You said it was fun.
妳曾說很開心吧
All my students are so cute, I love them.
學生們都很可愛，我很喜歡大家
How greeting the class gave you energy.
在教室對大家說早安，就能打起精神
How the school meals were delicious.
在教室吃的營養午餐也很美味
You loved your job,
妳如此熱愛妳的工作
do you really want to quit?
妳真的要辭職嗎？
I don't want you to regret this.
我不想讓妳後悔
-I… -Mom!
-我… -媽媽！
Where is science and engineering?
請問理工學系在哪邊？
-The booth is that way. -Thank you.
-攤位在那邊 -謝謝妳
If she sees you now…!
如果她現在見到妳的話…
You're right.
黑岩你說得對
I absolutely loved
我最喜歡
being a teacher.
老師的工作了
But do you remember what I told you?
不過你還記得我之前說過的話嗎？
To imagine the person you want to become and think of the steps you have to take.
先想像自己想成為什麼人 並思考你需要做些什麼
Can you picture the school?
腦中就能浮現想去的學校
So that's why
因此
I thought about it too.
我也想過了
Who I wanted to become.
自己想成為什麼人
I want to be me
我想當一個誠實的自己
and not live a lie anymore.
不再活在謊言中
Whatever happens,
無論發生什麼事
I want to take responsibility.
我都想負上責任
I want to be
我想
by your side.
待在你身邊
Me too.
我也是
I want to be by your side.
我想陪在老師身邊
From now until forever.
從現在直到永遠
Are you Hijiri Suenaga?
妳是末永聖小姐？
And Akira Kuroiwa?
和黑岩晶嗎？
-Yes. -Could we see some ID?
-是 -可以讓我看看證件嗎？
AKIRA KUROIWA HIJIRI SUENAGA
（黑岩晶，末永聖）
Excuse me.
不好意思
We received a call that a minor was kidnapped.
剛才有人報警說有未成年被誘拐
Would you mind coming to the station for some questioning?
我想問妳一些事情 能否跟我到警察局走一趟？
Next, I need a check on a woman.
接著，我需要查詢一名女性資料
One Hijiri Suenaga.
姓名是末永聖
THE FINALE IS NEXT!
（下一集是最終回！）
Kuroiwa, I'm glad I met you.
黑岩同學，能跟你相遇真是太好了
Subtitle translation by: Zensho Yamamoto
字幕翻譯：楊易